<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Tao Te Ching Simplified</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Tao Te Ching Simplified</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taonet.one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>We have moved Taonomics</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/we-have-moved-taonomics/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/we-have-moved-taonomics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/p/we-have-moved-taonomics/pantry.jpg" alt="Featured image of post We have moved Taonomics" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;taonomics-is-now-pantrynomicshttpssuperphysicsonepantrynomics-and-the-tao-network-is-the-pantry-points-systemhttpspantrypointscom&#34;&gt;Taonomics is now &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://superphysics.one/pantrynomics&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pantrynomics&lt;/a&gt; and the Tao Network is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pantrypoints.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Pantry Points System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is to shift our app&amp;rsquo;s focus from social networks into a practical moneyless system based on points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is now about the simplified version of the Tao Te Ching, which is the foundation of Pantrynomics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>71: Knowledge vs Opinion</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/71-knowledge-vs-opinion/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/71-knowledge-vs-opinion/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/parliament.jpg" alt="Featured image of post 71: Knowledge vs Opinion" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The highest attainment is to know and yet think we do not know. The highest disease is to not know and yet think that we do know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 It is simply by being pained at the thought of having this disease that we are preserved from it. The sage does not have this disease. He knows the pain that would be inseparable from it, and therefore he does not have it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>72: Ignorance</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/72-ignorance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/72-ignorance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/parliament.jpg" alt="Featured image of post 72: Ignorance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 When the people do not fear what they should fear, their great dread will come on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Let them not thoughtlessly indulge themselves in their ordinary life. Let them not act as if weary of what that life depends on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 It is by avoiding such indulgence that such weariness does not arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Therefore, the sage knows these things of himself, but does not parade his knowledge. He loves, but does not set a value on himself. Thus, he prefers humility &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; over exhibition.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>75: Economic Policy</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/75-economic-policy/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/75-economic-policy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/hand.jpg" alt="Featured image of post 75: Economic Policy" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The people suffer from famine because of the multitude of taxes consumed by their superiors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 The people are difficult to govern because of the excessive agency of their superiors in governing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 The people make light of dying because of the greatness of their labours in seeking for the means of living.
It is this which makes them think light of dying. Thus, it is that to leave the subject of living altogether out of view is better than to set a high value on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 70: Laws Should be Understandable</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-70-laws-should-be-understandable/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-70-laws-should-be-understandable/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/parliament.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 70: Laws Should be Understandable" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 My words are very easy to know, and very easy to practise. But there is no one in the world who is able to know and able to practise them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 There is an originating and all-comprehending principle in my words, and an authoritative law for the things which I enforce. It is because they do not know these, that men do not know me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 They who know me are few. This rarity makes me more prized. This is why the sage wears a poor garb of hair cloth, while he carries his signet of jade in his bosom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 73: Divine Justice </title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-73-divine-justice/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-73-divine-justice/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/parliament.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 73: Divine Justice " /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 He who defies the laws boldly &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is put to death. He who defies the law discretely &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; lives on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bold criminal appears to be injurious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sly criminal appears to be advantageous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Heaven&amp;rsquo;s anger [karma] smites the correct one. On this account, the sage feels a difficulty as to what to do without such action of Heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 It is the way of Heaven:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not to strive, and yet it skilfully overcomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not to speak, and yet it is skilful in obtaining a reply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not to call, and yet men come to it of themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its demonstrations are quiet, and yet its plans are skillful and effective.  The meshes of the net of Heaven are large and far apart, but lets nothing escape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 74: Death Penalty</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-74-death-penalty/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-74-death-penalty/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/parliament.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 74: Death Penalty" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 If the people do not fear death, why would anyone try to frighten them with death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the people were always afraid of death, then no one would do wrong if all the wrongdoers could be caught and be put to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; An executioner is like a great carpenter. He cuts wood without cutting his own hands!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 77: The Invisible Hand of the Tao</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-77-the-invisible-hand-of-the-tao/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-77-the-invisible-hand-of-the-tao/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/hand.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 77: The Invisible Hand of the Tao" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The Way (or Tao) of Heaven can be compared to the bending a bow. The part of the bow which was high is lowered. The part which was low is raised up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, Heaven reduces where there is superabundance, and supplements where there is deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 It is the Way of Heaven to reduce superabundance and to supplement deficiency. It is not so with the way of man. He takes away from those who have not enough to add to his own superabundance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Who can take his own superabundance and use it to serve all under heaven? Only he who is in possession of the Tao!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Therefore, the ruling sage acts without claiming the results as his. He achieves his merit and does not rest arrogantly in it. He does not wish to display his superiority.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 7: The Impartial Spectator</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-7-the-impartial-spectator/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-7-the-impartial-spectator/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/poverty.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 7: The Impartial Spectator" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The Tao thus creates Heaven and earth to last eternally for the sake of the Tao or True Nature, and not for the tao or Mother Nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Therefore, the knower of the Tao puts his own person last position, yet will be in the foremost position. He treats his self as if it were another self* in order to realize his Tao or True Nature. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; This allows his self to be impartial and avoid personal and private ends. This then allows him to realize those ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Translator&amp;rsquo;s Note: This is the impartial spectator technique mentioned by Adam Smith in the Theory of Moral Sentiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 8: Excellence is nearness to one&#39;s Tao or True Nature</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-8-excellence-is-nearness-to-ones-tao-or-true-nature/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-8-excellence-is-nearness-to-ones-tao-or-true-nature/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/poverty.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 8: Excellence is nearness to one&#39;s Tao or True Nature" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 This impartiality &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is like that of water. Water is impartial by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;benefitting all things,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;occupying the low place which all men dislike, without striving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, the impartiality of water is near to the impartiality of the Tao or True Nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The excellence of a house, or its nearness to the Tao, is in its good location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The excellence of the mind, or its nearness to the Tao, is in its abysmal stillness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The excellence of human relationships, or its nearness to the Tao, is in people being with the virtuous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The excellence of government, or its nearness to the Tao, is in its securing good order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The excellence of human affairs, or its nearness to the Tao, is in its ability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The excellence of any movement, or its nearness to the Tao, is in its timing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 We do not find fault with a person who is acting in his own excellence, no matter how low his position may be.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 9: Excellence is Prevented by Fetters</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-9-excellence-is-prevented-by-fetters/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-9-excellence-is-prevented-by-fetters/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/poverty.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 9: Excellence is Prevented by Fetters" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 It is better to leave a vessel unfilled, than to attempt to carry it when it is full. If you keep feeling a point that has been sharpened, the point cannot long preserve its sharpness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 When gold and jade fill the hall, their possessor cannot keep them safe. When wealth and honours lead to arrogancy, this brings its evil on itself. When the work is done, and one&amp;rsquo;s name is becoming distinguished, to withdraw into obscurity is the way of Heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 32: The Process of Creation</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-32-the-process-of-creation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-32-the-process-of-creation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/dharma600.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 32: The Process of Creation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The Tao or True Nature, considered as unchanging, has no name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 In its primordial simplicity it may be small. Yet the whole world dares not deal with (one embodying) it as a minister. If a king could guard and hold the Tao, everything would spontaneously submit themselves to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Heaven and Earth (under its guidance) unite together and send down the sweet dew, which, without the directions of men, reaches equally everywhere as of its own accord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 As soon as it proceeds to action, it has a name as the tao. Men can then know it. After they know it, they can be free from all risk of failure and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 The relation of the Tao to all the world is like that of the great rivers and seas to the streams from the valleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-6-creation-of-the-tao-from-the-tao&#34;&gt;Chapter 6: Creation of the tao from the Tao&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tao becomes the tao through the spirit of the female mystery [yin]. From this root, came creation. This sprit continues eternally acting gradually and gently, and without the touch of pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-22-the-two-forces-of-the-tao&#34;&gt;Chapter 22: The Two Forces of the Tao&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Tao comes the grandest forms of active force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These forces lead to the tao which we perceive with our eyes and touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the Tao, True Nature, Itself is hidden, though it shows Itself through the tao or nature which resembles It.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the Tao obscure while it is in the essences that endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those essences have the truth for those who can see it, whether in the distant past, present, or future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These forces work in sequence to create existence that continues forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know these things from knowing the Tao or True Nature of existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Part 15: Federal States</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/part-15-federal-states/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/part-15-federal-states/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/oraclecrop.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Part 15: Federal States" /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-57-the-state-should-have-concise-but-efficient-laws&#34;&gt;Chapter 57: The State Should Have Concise but Efficient Laws&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 A state may be ruled by measures of correction. Weapons of war may be used with crafty dexterity. But the kingdom is made one&amp;rsquo;s own only by freedom from action and purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 The multiplication of prohibitive laws increases the poverty of the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more implements to add to their profit that the people have, the greater disorder is there in the state and clan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more acts of crafty dexterity that men possess, the more do strange contrivances appear;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more display there is of legislation, the more thieves and robbers there are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Therefore a sage has said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 10: Life</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-10-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-10-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 10: Life" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 When the intelligent and animal souls are held together in one embrace by the tao, they can be kept from separating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the soul gives undivided attention to the vital breath [pranah], and brings it to the utmost degree of pliancy then he can become born*&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the soul has cleansed its imagination, it can become flawless [and die and leave the physical dimension].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Pranah is the glue that holds the soul to the body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; The tao can only begin and end creation as the female spirit [yin].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tao&amp;rsquo;s intelligence reaches every direction only because it has no knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tao can only love the people and rule the state through physical action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 The tao produces all things and nourishes them, without claim them as its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does all, and yet does not boast of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It presides over all, and yet does not control them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &amp;lsquo;The mysterious Quality&amp;rsquo; of the tao.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 13: Favor and Disgrace</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-13-favor-and-disgrace/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-13-favor-and-disgrace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 13: Favor and Disgrace" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The duality of the tao leads to the opposing perceptions of favour and disgrace, which would seem equally to be feared, in the same way as honour and great calamity are to be regarded as personal conditions of the same kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 What is meant by saying that favour and disgrace would seem equally to be feared?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disgrace is being in a low position after the enjoyment of favour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The getting of that favour leads to the apprehension of losing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The losing it leads to the fear of still greater calamity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it is mean to say that honour and great calamity are to be similarly regarded as personal conditions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes me liable to great calamity is my having the body which I call myself. If I did not have the body, no great calamity could come to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Therefore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a state&amp;rsquo;s governor should honour the state as he honours himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a state&amp;rsquo;s administrator should love the state as he loves himself. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 14: The Supreme Tao or the One has Physical and Metaphysical Dimensions</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-14-the-supreme-tao-or-the-one-has-physical-and-metaphysical-dimensions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-14-the-supreme-tao-or-the-one-has-physical-and-metaphysical-dimensions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/idea.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 14: The Supreme Tao or the One has Physical and Metaphysical Dimensions" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 We look at it, and we do not see it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Uniformity&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We listen to it, and we do not hear it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Inaudible.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We try to grasp it, and do not get hold of it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Subtle.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these three qualities, it cannot be made the subject of description; and hence we blend them together and obtain &amp;lsquo;The One&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Its upper part is not bright, and its lower part is not obscure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is ceaseless in its action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It cannot be named, and then it again returns and becomes nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is called:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Form of the Formless,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Semblance of the Invisible,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Fleeting and Indeterminable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 We meet it yet do not see its Front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We follow it yet we do not see its Back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;The unwinding the clue of the Tao&amp;rsquo; is when we can grasp the past tao in order to direct the present, knowing that the Tao of that tao is the same then and now. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 1: The Names of the Tao</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-1-the-names-of-the-tao/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-1-the-names-of-the-tao/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/p/chapter-1-the-names-of-the-tao/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 1: The Names of the Tao" /&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;unification-table&#34;&gt;Unification Table&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Hindu version&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Superphysics version&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Computer Analogy&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tao&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dharma&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;True Nature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design Specfications&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tao&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;rta dharma&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mother Nature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Design Constraints&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tao-Brahma&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brahma&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Totality of Existence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RAM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The One&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Saguna Brahma&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supreme Entity&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CPU&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mystery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maya&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Illusion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hardware limitations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; The Tao is &amp;lsquo;nature&amp;rsquo; and has two versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a plain nature &amp;lsquo;tao&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a True Nature &amp;lsquo;Tao&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plain nature is temporary, but the True Nature is unchanging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 As True Nature, the Tao is &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is the Originator of heaven and earth as the creative principle. As tao, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; it is Mother Nature&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; or the operating principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 If we want to discover the deep mystery of the Tao, we must always be without desire. But if we always have desire, we shall only see Its outer fringe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Under these two aspects, the Tao and the tao are really the same. But as development takes place, it receives different names. Together we call them the Mystery &amp;ndash; the deepest gate of all that is subtle and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 22: The Positive Force or Male Yang Unifies</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-22-the-positive-force-or-male-yang-unifies/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-22-the-positive-force-or-male-yang-unifies/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 22: The Positive Force or Male Yang Unifies" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The Positive Force makes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the partial complete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the crooked straight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the empty full&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the worn out new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He whose desires are few gets them. He whose desires are many goes astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Therefore the sage holds one thing&amp;ndash;humility&amp;ndash;and manifests it to all the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is free from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-display, and therefore he shines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-assertion, and therefore he is distinguished&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-boasting, and therefore his merit is acknowledged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-complacency, and therefore he acquires superiority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is because he is thus free from striving that therefore no one in the world is able to strive with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 That saying of the ancients that &amp;lsquo;the partial becomes complete&amp;rsquo; was not vainly spoken&amp;ndash;all real completion is comprehended under it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 24: The Brahma</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-24-the-brahma/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-24-the-brahma/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 24: The Brahma" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 There was something undefined and complete, coming into existence before Heaven and Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still and formless, standing alone, and undergoing no change. It reaches everywhere yet in no danger of being exhausted! &lt;strong&gt;It may be regarded as the Mother of all things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 I do not know its name, but I call it as an effect of the Way or Course of the Tao. Making an effort further, I call it Brahma [originally &amp;lsquo;The Great&amp;rsquo;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; The Brahma passes on in constant flow. Passing on, it becomes remote.
Having become remote, it returns. Therefore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tao [The Absolute] is Brahma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heaven [Metaphysics] is Brahma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earth [Physics] is Brahma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sage-king [Life] is also Brahma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, in the universe these four are Brahma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Man takes his law from the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Earth takes its law from Heaven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heaven takes its law from the Tao&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The law of the Tao or True Nature is Its being what It is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 28: Yin and Yang or Female and Male Force</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-28-yin-and-yang-or-female-and-male-force/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-28-yin-and-yang-or-female-and-male-force/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 28: Yin and Yang or Female and Male Force" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The male force has the female force in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows his manhood&amp;rsquo;s strength,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet still his female feebleness maintains;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to one channel flow the many drains,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All come to him, yea, all beneath the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This keeps his
Thus he keeps his nearness to the Tao or True Nature constantly. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
The simple child again, free from all stains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The white male yang force attracts, yet stays within the shade of the black female force.
This forms a pattern of humility in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence of creation, that is in line with the Tao or True Nature, returns endlessly to its first state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this, the glory of the Tao shines. Yet this glory loves disgrace as to lower itself to the bottom of creation from which everything rises up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unchanging nearness to the Tao completes its story. We hail in such a mind the simple infant mind inside it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Raw clay&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; when divided and distributed, forms vessels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sage, when employed, becomes the Head of all the officers of government. In his greatest regulations, he employs no violent measures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 2: Duality and Non-duality</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-2-duality-and-non-duality/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-2-duality-and-non-duality/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 2: Duality and Non-duality" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 We know ugliness by knowing the beauty of the beautiful. They know the lack of skill by knowing the skill of the skillful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 So it is that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;existence and non-existence give birth the one to the idea of the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;difficulty and ease produce the idea of the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;length and shortness fashion out the one the figure of the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the ideas of height and lowness arise from the contrast of the one with the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the musical notes and tones become harmonious through the relation of one with another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that being before and behind give the idea of one following another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Therefore, the knowers of the Tao or True Nature of affairs manages affairs without doing anything about the tao or nature, since the Tao is the cause and the tao is the effect. Likewise, they convey their instructions without speaking because the tao or nature follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 All things spring up. They grow and there is no claim made for their ownership. They go through their processes, and there is no expectation of a reward for the results. The work is accomplished, and there is no resting in it as an achievement. The work is done, but no one can see how. This makes the power not cease to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 30: Restraint</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-30-restraint/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-30-restraint/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 30: Restraint" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 He who assists a leader to be in harmony with the Tao or True Nature will not assert his mastery in the kingdom by force of arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a course is sure to meet with its proper return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Wherever a host is stationed, briars and thorns spring up. In the sequence of great armies, there are sure to be bad years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 A skilful commander strikes a decisive blow, and stops. He does not dare to continue his operations to assert and complete his mastery. He will strike the blow, but will be on his guard against being vain, boastful, or arrogant in consequence of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He strikes it as a matter of necessity&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 When things have attained their strong maturity they become old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not in accordance with the Tao. What is not in accordance with it soon comes to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 31: Weapons are Evil</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-31-weapons-are-evil/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-31-weapons-are-evil/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 31: Weapons are Evil" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 Weapons, however beautiful, are instruments of evil omen. These are hateful to all creatures. Therefore, they who have the Tao or True Nature do not like to employ them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 The superior man ordinarily considers the left hand the most honourable place, but in time of war the right hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those sharp weapons are instruments of evil omen, and not the instruments of the superior man, who uses them only when necessary. Instead, he uses calm and repose. Victory by force of arms is to him undesirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not desirable for him to delight in the slaughter of men. He who delights in the slaughter of men cannot get his will in the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 On occasions of festivity, being on the left hand is the prized position. On occasions of mourning, the right hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second in command of the army has his place on the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The general commanding in chief has his on the right.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His place, that is, is assigned to him as in the rites of mourning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who has killed many should weep for them with the bitterest grief. The victor in battle has his place according to those rites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 34: The tao of the Brahma</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-34-the-tao-of-the-brahma/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-34-the-tao-of-the-brahma/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 34: The tao of the Brahma" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 All-pervading is the Brahma! &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;  It may be found on the left hand and on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 All things depend on it for their production, which it gives to them, not one refusing obedience to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When its work is accomplished, it does not claim* the name of having done it. It clothes all things as with a garment, and makes no assumption of being their lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be named in the smallest things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All things return (to their root and disappear), and do not know that it is it which presides over their doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be named in the greatest things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Translator&amp;rsquo;s note: This is similar to Hinduism where the ego is detached from the effect of action&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Hence in the same way, the sage is able to accomplish his great achievements. It is through his not making himself great that he can accomplish them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 35: The Effects of the Brahma</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-35-the-effects-of-the-brahma/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-35-the-effects-of-the-brahma/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 35: The Effects of the Brahma" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The man who holds in his hands the knowledge of the Brahma&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, the whole world repairs. Men resort to him, and receive no hurt, but find rest, peace, and ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Music and dainties will make the passing guest stop for a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of the spoken Tao is inexhaustible, even if it &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; seems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;insipid and has no flavour, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not worth being looked at or listened to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 39: The Creations from the One</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-39-the-creations-from-the-one/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-39-the-creations-from-the-one/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 39: The Creations from the One" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The things which have the One from the begnning of time are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heaven [metaphysics] which by it is bright and pure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earth [physics] rendered thereby firm and sure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spirits [forces] with powers by it supplied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valleys [spacetime] kept full throughout their void&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All creatures [life] which through it do live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Princes and kings [destiny] who from it get the model which they give to all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these are the results of the One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Without purity, heaven would soon be torn apart.
Without firmness, the earth would break.
Without these powers, the spirits soon would fail.
Without fullness, the valley would be parched by drought.
Without life, creatures would die.
Without that moral sway, princes and kings would fall, however grand or high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Thus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dignity finds its origin in its previous meanness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lofty finds its stability in the lowness from which it rises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, princes and kings call themselves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;Orphans&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;Men of small virtue&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;Wheels without a hub&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By acknowledging their meanness, they see the foundation of their dignity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, we see the purpose of a wheel when we list its different parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kings wish to show themselves as elegant-looking as jade. But prefer to be coarse-looking as an ordinary stone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 3: Nothingness in the tao</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-3-nothingness-in-the-tao/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-3-nothingness-in-the-tao/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 3: Nothingness in the tao" /&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way to keep rivalry away from among the people is to not employ men of superior ability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way to keep people from becoming thieves is to not prize articles which are difficult to procure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way to keep their minds from disorder is to not show them what is likely to excite their desires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Therefore the sage, in the exercise of his government, empties their minds, fills their bellies, weakens their wills, and strengthens their bones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 He constantly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keeps them without knowledge and without desire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keeps those who have knowledge away from presuming to act on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When there is this abstinence from action, good order is universal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 40: The Tao and the tao</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-40-the-tao-and-the-tao/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-40-the-tao-and-the-tao/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 40: The Tao and the tao" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The movement of the Tao proceeds by contraries; [Positive-Negative]
Weakness marks the course of Tao&amp;rsquo;s mighty deeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 All things under heaven sprang from the Tao or True Nature as existing as the tao or nature. This nature sprang from the True Nature as originally non-existent and not named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-51-the-operation-of-the-tao-or-true-nature&#34;&gt;Chapter 51: The Operation of the Tao or True Nature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 All things are produced by the Tao, and nourished by Its outflowing operation. They receive their forms according to the tao of each, and are completed according to the circumstances of their condition. Therefore, all things honour the Tao or True Nature, and exalt Its outflowing operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 This honouring of the Tao and exalting of its operation is the result of a spontaneous tribute, and not any ordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Thus, the Tao produces all things, nourishes them, brings them to their full growth, nurses them, completes them, matures them, maintains them, and overspreads them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 It produces them and makes no claim of ownership of them. It carries them through their processes and does not vaunt its ability in doing so. It brings them to maturity and exercises no control over them. This is called Its &amp;lsquo;mysterious operation&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 42: The Three Gunas</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-42-the-three-gunas/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-42-the-three-gunas/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 42: The Three Gunas" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tao produced One. [Supreme Tao or God-consciousness]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One produced Two. [Duality]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two produced Three. [Three Gunas]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three produced All things. [Brahma or Mind of God or All Multiverses]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All things leave behind them the Obscurity out of which they have come, and go forward to embrace the Brightness into which they have emerged, while they are harmonised by the Breath of Nothingness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 What men dislike is to be orphans, to have little virtue, to be as carriages without naves; and yet these are the designations which kings and princes use for themselves. So it is that some things are increased by being diminished, and others are diminished by being increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 What other men (thus) teach, I also teach. The violent and strong do not die their natural death. I will make this the basis of my teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 49: Equipoise</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-49-equipoise/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-49-equipoise/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 49: Equipoise" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The sage has no invariable mind of his own. He makes the mind of the people his mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 I am good to those who are good to me and to those who are not good to me. Thus, all get to be good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sincere to those who are sincere with me and to those who are not sincere with me. Thus, all get to be sincere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 To the world, the sage has an appearance of indecision, and keeps his mind in a state of indifference to all. The people all keep their eyes and ears directed to him, and he deals with them all as his children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 51: The Operation of the Tao or True Nature</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-51-the-operation-of-the-tao-or-true-nature/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-51-the-operation-of-the-tao-or-true-nature/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 51: The Operation of the Tao or True Nature" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 All things are produced by the Tao, and nourished by Its outflowing operation. They receive their forms according to the tao of each, and are completed according to the circumstances of their condition. Therefore, all things honour the Tao or True Nature, and exalt Its outflowing operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 This honouring of the Tao and exalting of its operation is the result of a spontaneous tribute, and not any ordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Thus, the Tao produces all things, nourishes them, brings them to their full growth, nurses them, completes them, matures them, maintains them, and overspreads them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 It produces them and makes no claim of ownership of them. It carries them through their processes and does not vaunt its ability in doing so. It brings them to maturity and exercises no control over them. This is called Its &amp;lsquo;mysterious operation&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 52: We are the Children of the Tao or our True Nature</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-52-we-are-the-children-of-the-tao-or-our-true-nature/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-52-we-are-the-children-of-the-tao-or-our-true-nature/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 52: We are the Children of the Tao or our True Nature" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The Tao which originated all under the sky is to be considered as the mother of them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 When the mother is found, we know what her children should be. When a person knows that he is the child of the Tao or his own True Nature, and guards the qualities of the Tao that belong to him, then he will be free from all peril to the end of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 If he keeps closed his mouth and nostrils, then his life will be exempt from laborious exertion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If he keeps his mouth open and breathes to promote his selfish affairs, then his life will have no safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 The secret of clear-sightedness is the perception of what is small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret of strength is the guarding of what is soft and tender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 If he uses the light of the Tao his True Nature, he will revert to Its Source so bright. His body will ward all blight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 64: Good Intention</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-64-good-intention/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-64-good-intention/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 64: Good Intention" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 A thing at rest is easily kept hold of. It is easy to take measures against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That which is brittle is easily broken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That which is very small is easily dispersed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Action should be taken before a thing has made its appearance.  Order should be secured before disorder has begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 The large tree grew from the tiniest sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tower of nine storeys rose from a small heap of earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The journey of a thousand steps commenced with a single step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 He who acts with an ulterior purpose does harm. He who takes hold of a thing in the same way, loses his hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sage does not act so, and therefore does no harm. He does not lay hold so, and therefore does not lose his hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But people&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; are constantly ruining others when they are on the eve of success. Those successful people should be careful from start to end, to avoid being ruined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Therefore, the sage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;desires what other men do not desire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;does not prize things difficult to get&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learns what other men do not learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turns back to what the multitude of men have passed by&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, he helps the natural development of all things. He does not dare to act (with an ulterior purpose of his own).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 65: The Knowledge of Worldly Things</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-65-the-knowledge-of-worldly-things/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-65-the-knowledge-of-worldly-things/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 65: The Knowledge of Worldly Things" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 The ancients who showed their skill in practising the Tao or True Nature did so, not to enlighten the people, but rather to make them simple and ignorant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 The difficulty in governing the people arises from their having much knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He who governs a state by his wisdom is a scourge to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He who does not do so is a blessing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 The knowledge of these two things leads to a model for governance.  &amp;lsquo;The mysterious excellence of a governor&amp;rsquo; is the ability to know this model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such mysterious excellence deep and far-reaching. It shows its possessor as opposite to others, but leading them to a great conformity to him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 66: The Sage-Ruler is Humble Before the People</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-66-the-sage-ruler-is-humble-before-the-people/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-66-the-sage-ruler-is-humble-before-the-people/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 66: The Sage-Ruler is Humble Before the People" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 Rivers and seas are able to receive the water from the valleys by being lower than them. If water were homage and tribute, then the rivers and seas would be the kings of the valleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the sage-ruler, wishing to be above men:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;puts himself by his words below the people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;places his person behind them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 In this way, men do not feel his weight or feel injured even if he has his place above them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Therefore, the world delights to exalt him and are not weary of him. Because he does not strive, no one finds it possible to strive with him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 67: Patience, Frugality, Humility</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-67-patience-frugality-humility/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-67-patience-frugality-humility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 67: Patience, Frugality, Humility" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 All the world says that, while my Tao or personal True Nature is great, it appears to be inferior to other systems of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is just its greatness that makes it seem to be inferior. If it were like any other system, only its smallness would be known for a long time! &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 But I have three precious things which I prize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frugality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shrinking from taking precedence of others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 With that patience I can be bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With that frugality I can be spend a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shrinking from taking precedence of others, I can become a vessel of the highest honour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, they:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;give up &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; patience and are all for being rash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;give up frugality and are all for spending a lot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;give up being the last and seek only to be first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death is the last effect of all of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Patience is sure to be victorious even in battle, and can firmly maintain its ground. Heaven will save its possessor, by his very &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;patience protecting him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 68: The Proper Way to Deal with Adversity</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-68-the-proper-way-to-deal-with-adversity/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-68-the-proper-way-to-deal-with-adversity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 68: The Proper Way to Deal with Adversity" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has skill in the Tao&amp;rsquo;s wars, but assumes no martial ability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fights with most good, but will not resort to rage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;never contends, and this is his strength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bends Men&amp;rsquo;s wills to make them unite and matches Heaven&amp;rsquo;s ends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 69: The Defensive War</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-69-the-defensive-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-69-the-defensive-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/tao.png" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 69: The Defensive War" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 A master of the art of war has said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is called:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;marshalling the ranks where there are no ranks&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;baring the arms to fight where there are no arms to bare&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;grasping the weapon where there is no weapon to grasp&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;advancing against the enemy where there is no enemy&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 There greatest calamity is to lightly engage in war. This will lead to loss the loss of patience, which is most precious. When the weapons clash, the conqueror wins, but deplores his enemy&amp;rsquo;s calamitous loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-58-liberty&#34;&gt;Chapter 58: Liberty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 The government that seems the most unwise often supplies the most goodness to the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government which meddles and touches everything will &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; bring disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is found by the side of Misery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misery lurks beneath Happiness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows what either will come to in the end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Shall we then dispense with correction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method of correction shall by a turn become distortion. The good in it shall by a turn become evil.
The delusion of the people on this point has indeed subsisted for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Therefore the sage is (like) a square which cuts no one (with its angles); (like) a corner which injures no one (with its sharpness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is straightforward, but allows himself no license; he is bright, but does not dazzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-59-moderation&#34;&gt;Chapter 59: Moderation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Moderation is the best way to regulate the human&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and rendering the&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; service to the heavenly&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 It is only by this moderation that there becomes an early return to normalcy. That early return is what I call &amp;lsquo;the repeated accumulation of the attributes of the Tao&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repeated accumulation of those attributes leads to the subjugation of every obstacle each time. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
We do not know what shall be the limit of this subjugation. When one knows not what the limit shall be, he may be the ruler of a state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 He who possesses the mother of the state may rule a long time. He is like a plant with deep roots and firm flower stalks. These secure the plant for it to have a long life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-60-managing-the-state&#34;&gt;Chapter 60: Managing the State&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Governing a great state is like cooking small fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 The state should be governed according to the Tao or True Nature. In this way, the cooking up of criticism will not produce a bad smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that the cooking does not produce smells, but that the smells will not hurt men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that the smells could &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; hurt men, but because the ruling sage will not use it to hurt them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 When the ruler and his subjects do not injuriously affect each other, their good influences converge in the virtue of the Tao or True Nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-61-federalism&#34;&gt;Chapter 61: Federalism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 What makes a state great is its being like a low-lying, down-flowing stream. It becomes the centre to which tend all the small states under heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 This is shown by females. The female always overcomes the male by her stillness. Stillness may be considered a sort of abasement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Thus it is that a great state, by condescending to small states, gains them for itself. Here, the abasement leads to gaining adherents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small states, by abasing themselves to a great state, win it over to them. Here, the abasement leads to procuring favour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 The great state only wishes to unite men together and nourish them. A small state only wishes to be received by, and to serve, the other. Each gets what it desires, but the great state must learn to abase itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 4--The Tao is Nirguna or Nothingness</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-4-the-tao-is-nirguna-or-nothingness/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-4-the-tao-is-nirguna-or-nothingness/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://sorasystem.sirv.com/photos/space.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 4--The Tao is Nirguna or Nothingness" /&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 The Tao is like the emptiness of a vessel. In our use of it, we must be on our guard against all fullness.  How deep and unfathomable it is, as if it were the Honoured Ancestor of all things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 We should blunt our sharp points, and unravel the complications of things. We should attemper our brightness, and bring ourselves into agreement with the obscurity of others. How pure and still the Tao is, as if it would ever so continue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 I do not know where the Tao came from&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. It might appear to have been before God.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chapter 5: The Tao or True Nature is Nothingness, Yet is Omnipotent</title>
        <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-5-the-tao-or-true-nature-is-nothingness-yet-is-omnipotent/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-5-the-tao-or-true-nature-is-nothingness-yet-is-omnipotent/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://taonet.one/basketball600.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chapter 5: The Tao or True Nature is Nothingness, Yet is Omnipotent" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heaven and earth do not act from the impulse of any wish to be benevolent&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They deal with all things as the dogs of grass are dealt with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sages do not act from any wish to be benevolent.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They deal with the people as the dogs of grass are dealt with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 The space between heaven and earth can be compared to a bellows. It is emptied, but does not lose its power*. It is moved again to blow out more air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Translator&amp;rsquo;s Note: As Nirguna, the Tao is pure potentiality which technically doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
