<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 1: What is the Tao? on Tao Te Ching Simplified</title>
    <link>https://taonet.one/categories/part-1-what-is-the-tao/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 1: What is the Tao? on Tao Te Ching Simplified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taonet.one/categories/part-1-what-is-the-tao/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: Life</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-10-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-10-life/</guid>
      <description>1 When the intelligent and animal souls are held together in one embrace by the tao, they can be kept from separating.
 When the soul gives undivided attention to the vital breath [pranah], and brings it to the utmost degree of pliancy then he can become born*. When the soul has cleansed its imagination, it can become flawless [and die and leave the physical dimension].   *Pranah is the glue that holds the soul to the body</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13: Favor and Disgrace</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-13-favor-and-disgrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-13-favor-and-disgrace/</guid>
      <description>1 The duality of the tao leads to the opposing perceptions of favour and disgrace, which would seem equally to be feared, in the same way as honour and great calamity are to be regarded as personal conditions of the same kind.
2 What is meant by saying that favour and disgrace would seem equally to be feared?
 Disgrace is being in a low position after the enjoyment of favour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: The Names of the Tao</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-1-the-names-of-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-1-the-names-of-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>Unification Table    Tao Te Ching Hindu version Superphysics version Computer Analogy     Tao Dharma True Nature Design Specfications   tao rta dharma Mother Nature Design Constraints   Tao-Brahma Brahma Totality of Existence RAM   The One Saguna Brahma Supreme Entity CPU   Mystery Maya Illusion Hardware limitations    1 The Tao is &amp;lsquo;nature&amp;rsquo; and has two versions:
 a plain nature &amp;lsquo;tao&amp;rsquo; a True Nature &amp;lsquo;Tao&amp;rsquo;  The plain nature is temporary, but the True Nature is unchanging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Duality and Non-duality</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-2-duality-and-non-duality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-2-duality-and-non-duality/</guid>
      <description>1 We know ugliness by knowing the beauty of the beautiful. They know the lack of skill by knowing the skill of the skillful
2 So it is that:
 existence and non-existence give birth the one to the idea of the other difficulty and ease produce the idea of the other length and shortness fashion out the one the figure of the other the ideas of height and lowness arise from the contrast of the one with the other the musical notes and tones become harmonious through the relation of one with another that being before and behind give the idea of one following another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 39: The Creations from the One</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-39-the-creations-from-the-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-39-the-creations-from-the-one/</guid>
      <description>1 The things which have the One from the begnning of time are:
 Heaven [metaphysics] which by it is bright and pure Earth [physics] rendered thereby firm and sure Spirits [forces] with powers by it supplied Valleys [spacetime] kept full throughout their void All creatures [life] which through it do live Princes and kings [destiny] who from it get the model which they give to all.  All these are the results of the One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Nothingness in the tao</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-3-nothingness-in-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-3-nothingness-in-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>1
 The way to keep rivalry away from among the people is to not employ men of superior ability. The way to keep people from becoming thieves is to not prize articles which are difficult to procure. The way to keep their minds from disorder is to not show them what is likely to excite their desires.  2 Therefore the sage, in the exercise of his government, empties their minds, fills their bellies, weakens their wills, and strengthens their bones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
