<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patience on Tao Te Ching Simplified</title>
    <link>https://taonet.one/tags/patience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patience on Tao Te Ching Simplified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taonet.one/tags/patience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 31: Weapons are Evil</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-31-weapons-are-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-31-weapons-are-evil/</guid>
      <description>1 Weapons, however beautiful, are instruments of evil omen. These are hateful to all creatures. Therefore, they who have the Tao or True Nature do not like to employ them.
2 The superior man ordinarily considers the left hand the most honourable place, but in time of war the right hand.
Those sharp weapons are instruments of evil omen, and not the instruments of the superior man, who uses them only when necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 67: Patience, Frugality, Humility</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-67-patience-frugality-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-67-patience-frugality-humility/</guid>
      <description>1 All the world says that, while my Tao or personal True Nature is great, it appears to be inferior to other systems of teaching.
But it is just its greatness that makes it seem to be inferior. If it were like any other system, only its smallness would be known for a long time! 2 But I have three precious things which I prize:
   Frugality Shrinking from taking precedence of others  3 With that patience I can be bold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 68: The Proper Way to Deal with Adversity</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-68-the-proper-way-to-deal-with-adversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-68-the-proper-way-to-deal-with-adversity/</guid>
      <description>The sage:
 has skill in the Tao&amp;rsquo;s wars, but assumes no martial ability fights with most good, but will not resort to rage   never contends, and this is his strength bends Men&amp;rsquo;s wills to make them unite and matches Heaven&amp;rsquo;s ends  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 69: The Defensive War</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-69-the-defensive-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-69-the-defensive-war/</guid>
      <description>1 A master of the art of war has said:
This is called:
 &amp;lsquo;marshalling the ranks where there are no ranks&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;baring the arms to fight where there are no arms to bare&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;grasping the weapon where there is no weapon to grasp&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;advancing against the enemy where there is no enemy&amp;rsquo;  2 There greatest calamity is to lightly engage in war. This will lead to loss the loss of patience, which is most precious.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
