<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tao Te Ching Simplified</title>
    <link>https://taonet.one/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tao Te Ching Simplified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taonet.one/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We have moved Taonomics</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/we-have-moved-taonomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/we-have-moved-taonomics/</guid>
      <description>Taonomics is now Pantrynomics and the Tao Network is The Pantry Points System This is to shift our app&amp;rsquo;s focus from social networks into a practical moneyless system based on points.
This site is now about the simplified version of the Tao Te Ching, which is the foundation of Pantrynomics
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>71: Knowledge vs Opinion</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/71-knowledge-vs-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/71-knowledge-vs-opinion/</guid>
      <description>1 The highest attainment is to know and yet think we do not know. The highest disease is to not know and yet think that we do know.
2 It is simply by being pained at the thought of having this disease that we are preserved from it. The sage does not have this disease. He knows the pain that would be inseparable from it, and therefore he does not have it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>72: Ignorance</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/72-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/72-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>1 When the people do not fear what they should fear, their great dread will come on them.
2 Let them not thoughtlessly indulge themselves in their ordinary life. Let them not act as if weary of what that life depends on.
3 It is by avoiding such indulgence that such weariness does not arise.
4 Therefore, the sage knows these things of himself, but does not parade his knowledge. He loves, but does not set a value on himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>75: Economic Policy</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/75-economic-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/75-economic-policy/</guid>
      <description>1 The people suffer from famine because of the multitude of taxes consumed by their superiors.
2 The people are difficult to govern because of the excessive agency of their superiors in governing them.
3 The people make light of dying because of the greatness of their labours in seeking for the means of living. It is this which makes them think light of dying. Thus, it is that to leave the subject of living altogether out of view is better than to set a high value on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 70: Laws Should be Understandable</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-70-laws-should-be-understandable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-70-laws-should-be-understandable/</guid>
      <description>1 My words are very easy to know, and very easy to practise. But there is no one in the world who is able to know and able to practise them.
2 There is an originating and all-comprehending principle in my words, and an authoritative law for the things which I enforce. It is because they do not know these, that men do not know me.
3 They who know me are few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 73: Divine Justice </title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-73-divine-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-73-divine-justice/</guid>
      <description>1 He who defies the laws boldly is put to death. He who defies the law discretely lives on.
 The bold criminal appears to be injurious The sly criminal appears to be advantageous  But Heaven&amp;rsquo;s anger [karma] smites the correct one. On this account, the sage feels a difficulty as to what to do without such action of Heaven.
2 It is the way of Heaven:
 not to strive, and yet it skilfully overcomes not to speak, and yet it is skilful in obtaining a reply not to call, and yet men come to it of themselves  Its demonstrations are quiet, and yet its plans are skillful and effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 74: Death Penalty</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-74-death-penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-74-death-penalty/</guid>
      <description>1 If the people do not fear death, why would anyone try to frighten them with death?
If the people were always afraid of death, then no one would do wrong if all the wrongdoers could be caught and be put to death.
2 An executioner is like a great carpenter. He cuts wood without cutting his own hands!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 77: The Invisible Hand of the Tao</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-77-the-invisible-hand-of-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-77-the-invisible-hand-of-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>1 The Way (or Tao) of Heaven can be compared to the bending a bow. The part of the bow which was high is lowered. The part which was low is raised up.
Likewise, Heaven reduces where there is superabundance, and supplements where there is deficiency.
2 It is the Way of Heaven to reduce superabundance and to supplement deficiency. It is not so with the way of man. He takes away from those who have not enough to add to his own superabundance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: The Impartial Spectator</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-7-the-impartial-spectator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-7-the-impartial-spectator/</guid>
      <description>1 The Tao thus creates Heaven and earth to last eternally for the sake of the Tao or True Nature, and not for the tao or Mother Nature.
2 Therefore, the knower of the Tao puts his own person last position, yet will be in the foremost position. He treats his self as if it were another self* in order to realize his Tao or True Nature. This allows his self to be impartial and avoid personal and private ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8: Excellence is nearness to one&#39;s Tao or True Nature</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-8-excellence-is-nearness-to-ones-tao-or-true-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-8-excellence-is-nearness-to-ones-tao-or-true-nature/</guid>
      <description>1 This impartiality is like that of water. Water is impartial by:
 benefitting all things, occupying the low place which all men dislike, without striving  Hence, the impartiality of water is near to the impartiality of the Tao or True Nature.
2
 The excellence of a house, or its nearness to the Tao, is in its good location. The excellence of the mind, or its nearness to the Tao, is in its abysmal stillness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9: Excellence is Prevented by Fetters</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-9-excellence-is-prevented-by-fetters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-9-excellence-is-prevented-by-fetters/</guid>
      <description>1 It is better to leave a vessel unfilled, than to attempt to carry it when it is full. If you keep feeling a point that has been sharpened, the point cannot long preserve its sharpness.
2 When gold and jade fill the hall, their possessor cannot keep them safe. When wealth and honours lead to arrogancy, this brings its evil on itself. When the work is done, and one&amp;rsquo;s name is becoming distinguished, to withdraw into obscurity is the way of Heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 32: The Process of Creation</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-32-the-process-of-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-32-the-process-of-creation/</guid>
      <description>1 The Tao or True Nature, considered as unchanging, has no name.
2 In its primordial simplicity it may be small. Yet the whole world dares not deal with (one embodying) it as a minister. If a king could guard and hold the Tao, everything would spontaneously submit themselves to him.
3 Heaven and Earth (under its guidance) unite together and send down the sweet dew, which, without the directions of men, reaches equally everywhere as of its own accord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 15: Federal States</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/part-15-federal-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/part-15-federal-states/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 57: The State Should Have Concise but Efficient Laws 1 A state may be ruled by measures of correction. Weapons of war may be used with crafty dexterity. But the kingdom is made one&amp;rsquo;s own only by freedom from action and purpose.
2 The multiplication of prohibitive laws increases the poverty of the people.
The more implements to add to their profit that the people have, the greater disorder is there in the state and clan;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: Life</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-10-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-10-life/</guid>
      <description>1 When the intelligent and animal souls are held together in one embrace by the tao, they can be kept from separating.
 When the soul gives undivided attention to the vital breath [pranah], and brings it to the utmost degree of pliancy then he can become born*. When the soul has cleansed its imagination, it can become flawless [and die and leave the physical dimension].   *Pranah is the glue that holds the soul to the body</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13: Favor and Disgrace</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-13-favor-and-disgrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-13-favor-and-disgrace/</guid>
      <description>1 The duality of the tao leads to the opposing perceptions of favour and disgrace, which would seem equally to be feared, in the same way as honour and great calamity are to be regarded as personal conditions of the same kind.
2 What is meant by saying that favour and disgrace would seem equally to be feared?
 Disgrace is being in a low position after the enjoyment of favour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 14: The Supreme Tao or the One has Physical and Metaphysical Dimensions</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-14-the-supreme-tao-or-the-one-has-physical-and-metaphysical-dimensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-14-the-supreme-tao-or-the-one-has-physical-and-metaphysical-dimensions/</guid>
      <description>1 We look at it, and we do not see it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Uniformity.&amp;rsquo;
We listen to it, and we do not hear it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Inaudible.&amp;rsquo;
We try to grasp it, and do not get hold of it, and we name it &amp;lsquo;the Subtle.&amp;rsquo;
With these three qualities, it cannot be made the subject of description; and hence we blend them together and obtain &amp;lsquo;The One&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: The Names of the Tao</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-1-the-names-of-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-1-the-names-of-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>Unification Table    Tao Te Ching Hindu version Superphysics version Computer Analogy     Tao Dharma True Nature Design Specfications   tao rta dharma Mother Nature Design Constraints   Tao-Brahma Brahma Totality of Existence RAM   The One Saguna Brahma Supreme Entity CPU   Mystery Maya Illusion Hardware limitations    1 The Tao is &amp;lsquo;nature&amp;rsquo; and has two versions:
 a plain nature &amp;lsquo;tao&amp;rsquo; a True Nature &amp;lsquo;Tao&amp;rsquo;  The plain nature is temporary, but the True Nature is unchanging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 22: The Positive Force or Male Yang Unifies</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-22-the-positive-force-or-male-yang-unifies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-22-the-positive-force-or-male-yang-unifies/</guid>
      <description>1 The Positive Force makes:
 the partial complete the crooked straight the empty full the worn out new  He whose desires are few gets them. He whose desires are many goes astray.
2 Therefore the sage holds one thing&amp;ndash;humility&amp;ndash;and manifests it to all the world.
He is free from:
 self-display, and therefore he shines self-assertion, and therefore he is distinguished self-boasting, and therefore his merit is acknowledged self-complacency, and therefore he acquires superiority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 24: The Brahma</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-24-the-brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-24-the-brahma/</guid>
      <description>1 There was something undefined and complete, coming into existence before Heaven and Earth.
It was still and formless, standing alone, and undergoing no change. It reaches everywhere yet in no danger of being exhausted! It may be regarded as the Mother of all things.
2 I do not know its name, but I call it as an effect of the Way or Course of the Tao. Making an effort further, I call it Brahma [originally &amp;lsquo;The Great&amp;rsquo;].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 28: Yin and Yang or Female and Male Force</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-28-yin-and-yang-or-female-and-male-force/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-28-yin-and-yang-or-female-and-male-force/</guid>
      <description>The male force has the female force in it.
Who knows his manhood&amp;rsquo;s strength,
Yet still his female feebleness maintains;
As to one channel flow the many drains,
All come to him, yea, all beneath the sky.
This keeps his Thus he keeps his nearness to the Tao or True Nature constantly. The simple child again, free from all stains.
The white male yang force attracts, yet stays within the shade of the black female force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Duality and Non-duality</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-2-duality-and-non-duality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-2-duality-and-non-duality/</guid>
      <description>1 We know ugliness by knowing the beauty of the beautiful. They know the lack of skill by knowing the skill of the skillful
2 So it is that:
 existence and non-existence give birth the one to the idea of the other difficulty and ease produce the idea of the other length and shortness fashion out the one the figure of the other the ideas of height and lowness arise from the contrast of the one with the other the musical notes and tones become harmonious through the relation of one with another that being before and behind give the idea of one following another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 30: Restraint</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-30-restraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-30-restraint/</guid>
      <description>1 He who assists a leader to be in harmony with the Tao or True Nature will not assert his mastery in the kingdom by force of arms.
Such a course is sure to meet with its proper return.
2 Wherever a host is stationed, briars and thorns spring up. In the sequence of great armies, there are sure to be bad years.
3 A skilful commander strikes a decisive blow, and stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 31: Weapons are Evil</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-31-weapons-are-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-31-weapons-are-evil/</guid>
      <description>1 Weapons, however beautiful, are instruments of evil omen. These are hateful to all creatures. Therefore, they who have the Tao or True Nature do not like to employ them.
2 The superior man ordinarily considers the left hand the most honourable place, but in time of war the right hand.
Those sharp weapons are instruments of evil omen, and not the instruments of the superior man, who uses them only when necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 34: The tao of the Brahma</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-34-the-tao-of-the-brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-34-the-tao-of-the-brahma/</guid>
      <description>1 All-pervading is the Brahma! It may be found on the left hand and on the right.
2 All things depend on it for their production, which it gives to them, not one refusing obedience to it.
When its work is accomplished, it does not claim* the name of having done it. It clothes all things as with a garment, and makes no assumption of being their lord.
It may be named in the smallest things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 35: The Effects of the Brahma</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-35-the-effects-of-the-brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-35-the-effects-of-the-brahma/</guid>
      <description>1 The man who holds in his hands the knowledge of the Brahma, the whole world repairs. Men resort to him, and receive no hurt, but find rest, peace, and ease.
2 Music and dainties will make the passing guest stop for a time.
The use of the spoken Tao is inexhaustible, even if it seems:
 insipid and has no flavour, and not worth being looked at or listened to  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 39: The Creations from the One</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-39-the-creations-from-the-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-39-the-creations-from-the-one/</guid>
      <description>1 The things which have the One from the begnning of time are:
 Heaven [metaphysics] which by it is bright and pure Earth [physics] rendered thereby firm and sure Spirits [forces] with powers by it supplied Valleys [spacetime] kept full throughout their void All creatures [life] which through it do live Princes and kings [destiny] who from it get the model which they give to all.  All these are the results of the One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Nothingness in the tao</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-3-nothingness-in-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-3-nothingness-in-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>1
 The way to keep rivalry away from among the people is to not employ men of superior ability. The way to keep people from becoming thieves is to not prize articles which are difficult to procure. The way to keep their minds from disorder is to not show them what is likely to excite their desires.  2 Therefore the sage, in the exercise of his government, empties their minds, fills their bellies, weakens their wills, and strengthens their bones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 40: The Tao and the tao</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-40-the-tao-and-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-40-the-tao-and-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>1 The movement of the Tao proceeds by contraries; [Positive-Negative] Weakness marks the course of Tao&amp;rsquo;s mighty deeds.
2 All things under heaven sprang from the Tao or True Nature as existing as the tao or nature. This nature sprang from the True Nature as originally non-existent and not named.
Chapter 51: The Operation of the Tao or True Nature 1 All things are produced by the Tao, and nourished by Its outflowing operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 42: The Three Gunas</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-42-the-three-gunas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-42-the-three-gunas/</guid>
      <description>1
 The Tao produced One. [Supreme Tao or God-consciousness] One produced Two. [Duality] Two produced Three. [Three Gunas] Three produced All things. [Brahma or Mind of God or All Multiverses]  All things leave behind them the Obscurity out of which they have come, and go forward to embrace the Brightness into which they have emerged, while they are harmonised by the Breath of Nothingness.
2 What men dislike is to be orphans, to have little virtue, to be as carriages without naves; and yet these are the designations which kings and princes use for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 49: Equipoise</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-49-equipoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-49-equipoise/</guid>
      <description>1 The sage has no invariable mind of his own. He makes the mind of the people his mind.
2 I am good to those who are good to me and to those who are not good to me. Thus, all get to be good.
I am sincere to those who are sincere with me and to those who are not sincere with me. Thus, all get to be sincere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 51: The Operation of the Tao or True Nature</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-51-the-operation-of-the-tao-or-true-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-51-the-operation-of-the-tao-or-true-nature/</guid>
      <description>1 All things are produced by the Tao, and nourished by Its outflowing operation. They receive their forms according to the tao of each, and are completed according to the circumstances of their condition. Therefore, all things honour the Tao or True Nature, and exalt Its outflowing operation.
2 This honouring of the Tao and exalting of its operation is the result of a spontaneous tribute, and not any ordination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 52: We are the Children of the Tao or our True Nature</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-52-we-are-the-children-of-the-tao-or-our-true-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-52-we-are-the-children-of-the-tao-or-our-true-nature/</guid>
      <description>1 The Tao which originated all under the sky is to be considered as the mother of them all.
2 When the mother is found, we know what her children should be. When a person knows that he is the child of the Tao or his own True Nature, and guards the qualities of the Tao that belong to him, then he will be free from all peril to the end of his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 64: Good Intention</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-64-good-intention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-64-good-intention/</guid>
      <description>1 A thing at rest is easily kept hold of. It is easy to take measures against it.
 That which is brittle is easily broken. That which is very small is easily dispersed.  Action should be taken before a thing has made its appearance. Order should be secured before disorder has begun.
2 The large tree grew from the tiniest sprout.
 The tower of nine storeys rose from a small heap of earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 65: The Knowledge of Worldly Things</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-65-the-knowledge-of-worldly-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-65-the-knowledge-of-worldly-things/</guid>
      <description>1 The ancients who showed their skill in practising the Tao or True Nature did so, not to enlighten the people, but rather to make them simple and ignorant.
2 The difficulty in governing the people arises from their having much knowledge.
 He who governs a state by his wisdom is a scourge to it. He who does not do so is a blessing.  3 The knowledge of these two things leads to a model for governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 66: The Sage-Ruler is Humble Before the People</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-66-the-sage-ruler-is-humble-before-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-66-the-sage-ruler-is-humble-before-the-people/</guid>
      <description>1 Rivers and seas are able to receive the water from the valleys by being lower than them. If water were homage and tribute, then the rivers and seas would be the kings of the valleys.
Likewise, the sage-ruler, wishing to be above men:
 puts himself by his words below the people places his person behind them  2 In this way, men do not feel his weight or feel injured even if he has his place above them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 67: Patience, Frugality, Humility</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-67-patience-frugality-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-67-patience-frugality-humility/</guid>
      <description>1 All the world says that, while my Tao or personal True Nature is great, it appears to be inferior to other systems of teaching.
But it is just its greatness that makes it seem to be inferior. If it were like any other system, only its smallness would be known for a long time! 2 But I have three precious things which I prize:
   Frugality Shrinking from taking precedence of others  3 With that patience I can be bold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 68: The Proper Way to Deal with Adversity</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-68-the-proper-way-to-deal-with-adversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-68-the-proper-way-to-deal-with-adversity/</guid>
      <description>The sage:
 has skill in the Tao&amp;rsquo;s wars, but assumes no martial ability fights with most good, but will not resort to rage   never contends, and this is his strength bends Men&amp;rsquo;s wills to make them unite and matches Heaven&amp;rsquo;s ends  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 69: The Defensive War</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-69-the-defensive-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-69-the-defensive-war/</guid>
      <description>1 A master of the art of war has said:
This is called:
 &amp;lsquo;marshalling the ranks where there are no ranks&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;baring the arms to fight where there are no arms to bare&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;grasping the weapon where there is no weapon to grasp&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;advancing against the enemy where there is no enemy&amp;rsquo;  2 There greatest calamity is to lightly engage in war. This will lead to loss the loss of patience, which is most precious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 58: Liberty 1 The government that seems the most unwise often supplies the most goodness to the people.
The government which meddles and touches everything will bring disappointment.
Happiness is found by the side of Misery.
Misery lurks beneath Happiness!
Who knows what either will come to in the end?
2 Shall we then dispense with correction?
The method of correction shall by a turn become distortion. The good in it shall by a turn become evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4--The Tao is Nirguna or Nothingness</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-4-the-tao-is-nirguna-or-nothingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-4-the-tao-is-nirguna-or-nothingness/</guid>
      <description>1 The Tao is like the emptiness of a vessel. In our use of it, we must be on our guard against all fullness. How deep and unfathomable it is, as if it were the Honoured Ancestor of all things!
2 We should blunt our sharp points, and unravel the complications of things. We should attemper our brightness, and bring ourselves into agreement with the obscurity of others. How pure and still the Tao is, as if it would ever so continue!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: The Tao or True Nature is Nothingness, Yet is Omnipotent</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-5-the-tao-or-true-nature-is-nothingness-yet-is-omnipotent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-5-the-tao-or-true-nature-is-nothingness-yet-is-omnipotent/</guid>
      <description>1
 Heaven and earth do not act from the impulse of any wish to be benevolent.  They deal with all things as the dogs of grass are dealt with.   The sages do not act from any wish to be benevolent.  They deal with the people as the dogs of grass are dealt with.    2 The space between heaven and earth can be compared to a bellows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
