<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 4: Creation and the Two Forces on Tao Te Ching Simplified</title>
    <link>https://taonet.one/categories/part-4-creation-and-the-two-forces/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 4: Creation and the Two Forces on Tao Te Ching Simplified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taonet.one/categories/part-4-creation-and-the-two-forces/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 32: The Process of Creation</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-32-the-process-of-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-32-the-process-of-creation/</guid>
      <description>1 The Tao or True Nature, considered as unchanging, has no name.
2 In its primordial simplicity it may be small. Yet the whole world dares not deal with (one embodying) it as a minister. If a king could guard and hold the Tao, everything would spontaneously submit themselves to him.
3 Heaven and Earth (under its guidance) unite together and send down the sweet dew, which, without the directions of men, reaches equally everywhere as of its own accord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 22: The Positive Force or Male Yang Unifies</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-22-the-positive-force-or-male-yang-unifies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-22-the-positive-force-or-male-yang-unifies/</guid>
      <description>1 The Positive Force makes:
 the partial complete the crooked straight the empty full the worn out new  He whose desires are few gets them. He whose desires are many goes astray.
2 Therefore the sage holds one thing&amp;ndash;humility&amp;ndash;and manifests it to all the world.
He is free from:
 self-display, and therefore he shines self-assertion, and therefore he is distinguished self-boasting, and therefore his merit is acknowledged self-complacency, and therefore he acquires superiority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 28: Yin and Yang or Female and Male Force</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-28-yin-and-yang-or-female-and-male-force/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-28-yin-and-yang-or-female-and-male-force/</guid>
      <description>The male force has the female force in it.
Who knows his manhood&amp;rsquo;s strength,
Yet still his female feebleness maintains;
As to one channel flow the many drains,
All come to him, yea, all beneath the sky.
This keeps his Thus he keeps his nearness to the Tao or True Nature constantly. The simple child again, free from all stains.
The white male yang force attracts, yet stays within the shade of the black female force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 30: Restraint</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-30-restraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-30-restraint/</guid>
      <description>1 He who assists a leader to be in harmony with the Tao or True Nature will not assert his mastery in the kingdom by force of arms.
Such a course is sure to meet with its proper return.
2 Wherever a host is stationed, briars and thorns spring up. In the sequence of great armies, there are sure to be bad years.
3 A skilful commander strikes a decisive blow, and stops.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
