<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brahma on Tao Te Ching Simplified</title>
    <link>https://taonet.one/tags/brahma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brahma on Tao Te Ching Simplified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taonet.one/tags/brahma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 24: The Brahma</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-24-the-brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-24-the-brahma/</guid>
      <description>1 There was something undefined and complete, coming into existence before Heaven and Earth.
It was still and formless, standing alone, and undergoing no change. It reaches everywhere yet in no danger of being exhausted! It may be regarded as the Mother of all things.
2 I do not know its name, but I call it as an effect of the Way or Course of the Tao. Making an effort further, I call it Brahma [originally &amp;lsquo;The Great&amp;rsquo;].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 34: The tao of the Brahma</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-34-the-tao-of-the-brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-34-the-tao-of-the-brahma/</guid>
      <description>1 All-pervading is the Brahma! It may be found on the left hand and on the right.
2 All things depend on it for their production, which it gives to them, not one refusing obedience to it.
When its work is accomplished, it does not claim* the name of having done it. It clothes all things as with a garment, and makes no assumption of being their lord.
It may be named in the smallest things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 35: The Effects of the Brahma</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-35-the-effects-of-the-brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-35-the-effects-of-the-brahma/</guid>
      <description>1 The man who holds in his hands the knowledge of the Brahma, the whole world repairs. Men resort to him, and receive no hurt, but find rest, peace, and ease.
2 Music and dainties will make the passing guest stop for a time.
The use of the spoken Tao is inexhaustible, even if it seems:
 insipid and has no flavour, and not worth being looked at or listened to  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 42: The Three Gunas</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-42-the-three-gunas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-42-the-three-gunas/</guid>
      <description>1
 The Tao produced One. [Supreme Tao or God-consciousness] One produced Two. [Duality] Two produced Three. [Three Gunas] Three produced All things. [Brahma or Mind of God or All Multiverses]  All things leave behind them the Obscurity out of which they have come, and go forward to embrace the Brightness into which they have emerged, while they are harmonised by the Breath of Nothingness.
2 What men dislike is to be orphans, to have little virtue, to be as carriages without naves; and yet these are the designations which kings and princes use for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
