<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Brahma on Tao Te Ching Simplified</title>
    <link>https://taonet.one/tags/the-brahma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Brahma on Tao Te Ching Simplified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taonet.one/tags/the-brahma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 40: The Tao and the tao</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-40-the-tao-and-the-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-40-the-tao-and-the-tao/</guid>
      <description>1 The movement of the Tao proceeds by contraries; [Positive-Negative] Weakness marks the course of Tao&amp;rsquo;s mighty deeds.
2 All things under heaven sprang from the Tao or True Nature as existing as the tao or nature. This nature sprang from the True Nature as originally non-existent and not named.
Chapter 51: The Operation of the Tao or True Nature 1 All things are produced by the Tao, and nourished by Its outflowing operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 51: The Operation of the Tao or True Nature</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-51-the-operation-of-the-tao-or-true-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-51-the-operation-of-the-tao-or-true-nature/</guid>
      <description>1 All things are produced by the Tao, and nourished by Its outflowing operation. They receive their forms according to the tao of each, and are completed according to the circumstances of their condition. Therefore, all things honour the Tao or True Nature, and exalt Its outflowing operation.
2 This honouring of the Tao and exalting of its operation is the result of a spontaneous tribute, and not any ordination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 52: We are the Children of the Tao or our True Nature</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-52-we-are-the-children-of-the-tao-or-our-true-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-52-we-are-the-children-of-the-tao-or-our-true-nature/</guid>
      <description>1 The Tao which originated all under the sky is to be considered as the mother of them all.
2 When the mother is found, we know what her children should be. When a person knows that he is the child of the Tao or his own True Nature, and guards the qualities of the Tao that belong to him, then he will be free from all peril to the end of his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 64: Good Intention</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-64-good-intention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-64-good-intention/</guid>
      <description>1 A thing at rest is easily kept hold of. It is easy to take measures against it.
 That which is brittle is easily broken. That which is very small is easily dispersed.  Action should be taken before a thing has made its appearance. Order should be secured before disorder has begun.
2 The large tree grew from the tiniest sprout.
 The tower of nine storeys rose from a small heap of earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 65: The Knowledge of Worldly Things</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-65-the-knowledge-of-worldly-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-65-the-knowledge-of-worldly-things/</guid>
      <description>1 The ancients who showed their skill in practising the Tao or True Nature did so, not to enlighten the people, but rather to make them simple and ignorant.
2 The difficulty in governing the people arises from their having much knowledge.
 He who governs a state by his wisdom is a scourge to it. He who does not do so is a blessing.  3 The knowledge of these two things leads to a model for governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 66: The Sage-Ruler is Humble Before the People</title>
      <link>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-66-the-sage-ruler-is-humble-before-the-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://taonet.one/p/chapter-66-the-sage-ruler-is-humble-before-the-people/</guid>
      <description>1 Rivers and seas are able to receive the water from the valleys by being lower than them. If water were homage and tribute, then the rivers and seas would be the kings of the valleys.
Likewise, the sage-ruler, wishing to be above men:
 puts himself by his words below the people places his person behind them  2 In this way, men do not feel his weight or feel injured even if he has his place above them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
